// questions.js

const questions = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "1.A leader can be anyone who serves as an effective ____.",
    options: [
      "patriarch",
      "narcissist",
      "social change agent",
      "politician",
      "manipulator"
    ],
    answer: "social change agent"
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "2.____ is the central concept in the case of leadership.",
    options: [
      "Authority",
      "Influence",
      "Coercion",
      "Knowledge",
      "Relationship"
    ],
    answer: "Influence"
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "3.Which of the following is the 21st century slogan for leadership that is replacing earlier emphasis on instructional leadership?",
    options: [
      "'Leadership for learning'",
      "'Leadership for power'",
      "'Leadership for control'",
      "'Leadership for educational institutes'",
      "'Leadership for society'"
    ],
    answer: "'Leadership for learning'"
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "4.The current focus of educational leadership is to produce ____ who can construct effective solutions for critical social problems.",
    options: [
      "politicians",
      "transactional leaders",
      "transformational leaders",
      "negotiable leaders",
      "kings"
    ],
    answer: "transformational leaders"
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "5.21st century leaders need to have ____ in addition to new knowledge and skills.",
    options: [
      "low maturity",
      "high emotional wisdom",
      "low spiritual wisdom",
      "high emotional immaturity",
      "low adjustability"
    ],
    answer: "high emotional wisdom"
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "6.Authentic learning is about ____.",
    options: [
      "developing the capability to give one's unique contribution to others",
      "only taking new knowledge & skills for oneself",
      "exclusively focusing on personal growth",
      "learning from trustable sources",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    answer: "developing the capability to give one's unique contribution to others"
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "7.Which of the following is not linked with leadership?",
    options: [
      "Influence",
      "Values",
      "Ethics",
      "Vision",
      "Oppression"
    ],
    answer: "Oppression"
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "8.One of the goals of present day educational leadership is to build a ____ as a ____.",
    options: [
      "toxic culture, treatment for the organization",
      "pessimist culture, way of life",
      "learning culture, method of forcing employees",
      "learning culture, way of life",
      "college, way of life"
    ],
    answer: "learning culture, way of life"
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "9.An issue of educational leadership is providing a ____ driven vision.",
    options: [
      "power",
      "politics",
      "value",
      "control",
      "authority"
    ],
    answer: "value"
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "10.In the PRES model of authentic leadership, S stands for ____.",
    options: [
      "self-expression",
      "self-control",
      "self-love",
      "self-knowledge",
      "stability"
    ],
    answer: "self-knowledge"
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "11.Capable Educational leaders need to possess _______.",
    options: [
      "Good listening skills",
      "Emotional intelligence",
      "Ability to generate positive changes",
      "Ability for critical reflection & future vision",
      "All the above"
    ],
    answer: "All the above"
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "12.Positional authority is independent of leadership but not related to_______.",
    options: [
      "Influencing people",
      "judging others",
      "intention to achieve",
      "values,ethics & vision",
      "policy making"
    ],
    answer: "judging others"
  },

  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "13.Professional Education is concerned with the following main aspects of development except __",
    answer: "ability to exact control",
    options: [
      "professional knowledge base",
      "ability to exact control",
      "confidence in professional action",
      "development of reflection"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "14.CPD stands for __",
    answer: "Continuous Professional Development",
    options: [
      "Collaborative Professional Development",
      "Continuous Professional Development",
      "Continuous Pedagogical Development",
      "Critical Personal Development",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "15.Which of the following is not a characteristic of 21st century learners?",
    answer: "Maladaptive",
    options: [
      "Tech-savvy",
      "Creative",
      "Networkers",
      "Reliant on media",
      "Maladaptive"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 16,
    question: "16.Which of the following is a characteristic of 21st century educators?",
    answer: "adapting to ICT",
    options: [
      "self-centric",
      "resistor",
      "adapting to ICT",
      "fixed on one curriculum or learning style",
      "self-absorbed"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 17,
    question: "17.In learner-centric systems, active learning can be encouraged by using __",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "game-based learning",
      "mobile apps",
      "flipped classes",
      "None of the above",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 18,
    question: "18.Thinking about teaching & always improving it in innovative ways is called __.",
    answer: "Reflective practice",
    options: [
      "Reflective practice",
      "Retractive practice",
      "Refractive practice",
      "Learning pedagogy",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 19,
    question: "19.Which of the following is not one of the steps in the 5-step model of problem solving?",
    answer: "Incubation",
    options: [
      "hypothesizing",
      "Reasoning",
      "Putting up questions",
      "Testing",
      "Incubation"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 20,
    question: "20.Highest level of reflection leads to __",
    answer: "worthwhileness",
    options: [
      "worthwhileness",
      "worthlessness",
      "worthiness",
      "reflective actualization",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 21,
    question: "21.Which of the following is not one of the perspectives given by Brookfield for reflective practice?",
    answer: "society",
    options: [
      "practitioners",
      "colleagues",
      "society",
      "learners",
      "established theory"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 22,
    question: "22.The __ area of the Johari window refers to the area that you are unaware of and that can be reduced by asking others for more transparent feedback.",
    answer: "blind",
    options: [
      "open",
      "blind",
      "hidden",
      "unknown",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 23,
    question: "23.'Problem-based learning' focuses on ---",
    answer: "Students learn through analyzing & solving a problem",
    options: [
      "Course completion & examination",
      "Students need to demonstrate curricular activities",
      "Teachers to teach less and learn more",
      "Students need to demonstrate domain-specific knowledge",
      "Certification of degrees by colleges",
      "Students learn through analyzing & solving a problem"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 24,
    question: "24.The concept of Continuous Professional development comprehensively means---",
    answer: "Enhancing effectiveness as a researcher & teacher",
    options: [
      "Pedagogical skill development",
      "Professional action",
      "Updated curricula & technology",
      "Academic environment",
      "Enhancing effectiveness as a researcher & teacher",
      "Qualifying for Teaching license"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 25,
    question: "25.__in education are valuable code of conducts exhibited & enforced by teachers in relation to the students, colleges, community and to oneself for positive educational consequences",
    answer: "Professional ethics",
    options: [
      "Professional ethics",
      "Formal rules",
      "Violations",
      "Professional relations",
      "Committee relations"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 26,
    question: "26.The principles that teachersâ€™ Code of Professional Practice is to be based on include",
    answer: "all of the above",
    options: [
      "accountability",
      "service to the public",
      "responsiveness to the Government & the needs of the public",
      "fairness and integrity",
      "all of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 27,
    question: "27.__of educational institutes leading towards consequences like commercialization of degrees, low quality teaching and no job security is one of the current ethical challenges in the teaching profession.",
    answer: "Privatization",
    options: [
      "Personalization",
      "Industrialization",
      "Privatization",
      "Institutionalization",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 28,
    question: "28.Which of the following are current ethical issues and challenges in the teaching profession?",
    answer: "a, b and c",
    options: [
      "Political interference",
      "Corruption",
      "Communication and cultural barriers",
      "Only b and c",
      "a, b and c"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 29,
    question: "29.Each teacher has an obligation to ____",
    answer: "demonstrate high standards of professional practice",
    options: [
      "disrespect the opinion that goes against their own",
      "not care about students",
      "encourage harassment at workplace",
      "demonstrate high standards of professional practice",
      "stay away from parents and guardians"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 30,
    question: "30.The code of professional practice should be ___",
    answer: "updated time to time",
    options: [
      "discriminatory",
      "updated time to time",
      "kept the same forever",
      "optional for a teacher to follow or not",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 31,
    question: "31.Teachers serve the public interest by the following, except",
    answer: "favoring certain students over others",
    options: [
      "favoring certain students over others",
      "being committed to students' learning",
      "working in partnership with parents",
      "exercising reasonable care",
      "Collaborating with all stakeholders"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 32,
    question: "32.Teachers should",
    answer: "motivate and inspire pupils",
    options: [
      "ignore specific needs of pupils",
      "motivate and inspire pupils",
      "work only in isolation",
      "not include parents in the process",
      "decide which pupils they like and which they don't"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 33,
    question: "33.The process of ethical teaching should begin from pre-service studentship & ______",
    answer: "continue throughout professional life",
    options: [
      "stop there",
      "continue for a year",
      "continue till the teacher gets tired",
      "continue throughout professional life",
      "stop when the head asks"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 34,
    question: "34.At the time of ethical dilemma an inspirational educational leader should do-----",
    answer: "All the above",
    options: [
      "Clarify the facts & check the data",
      "Take strategic decision & act upon carefully",
      "Imagine several options for solutions",
      "Evaluate options using different approaches",
      "All the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 35,
    question: "35.The educational leaders also must incorporate __________-as part of their thinking & reasoning as ethics is at the core of a given human enterprise.",
    answer: "ethical analysis",
    options: [
      "cooperate & collaborate with other agencies",
      "conditionally work with others",
      "ethical analysis",
      "engaging themselves in recreational activities",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:36,
    question: "36.According to the ability model, emotional intelligence consists of 4 abilities given below, except.",
    options: [
      "Perceiving emotions",
      "Using emotions",
      "Ignoring emotions",
      "Understanding emotions",
      "Managing emotions"
    ],
    answer:"Ignoring emotions"
  },
  {
    numb:37,
    question: "37.Who among the following gave the mixed model of intelligence and focused on the importance of emotional intelligence as compared to IQ?",
    options: [
      "Goleman",
      "Maslow",
      "Salovey and Mayer",
      "Watson",
      "Freud"
    ],
    answer:"Goleman"
  },
  {
    numb:38,
    question: "38.Which leadership style gives the message: 'try this'",
    options: [
      "Coercive",
      "Authoritative",
      "Democratic",
      "Affiliative",
      "Coaching"
    ],
    answer:"Coaching"
  },
  {
     numb:39,
    question: "39.Which of the following is not a trait of transformational leaders?",
    options: [
      "Idealized influence",
      "Inspirational motivation",
      "Coercive authority",
      "Individualized consideration",
      "Intellectual Stimulation"
    ],
    answer:"Coercive authority"
  },
  {
     numb:40,
    question: "40.___ is a social process by which emotions are shared collectively across a group in a social context.",
    options: [
      "Social emotion",
      "Emotional labor",
      "Emotional regulation",
      "Emotional socialization",
      "Emotional contagion"
    ],
    answer:"Emotional contagion"
  },
  {
     numb:41,
    question: "41.___ includes modifying initial feelings by changing the situation or cognitions of the situation",
    options: [
      "Response-focused regulation",
      "Social regulation",
      "Emotional labor",
      "Antecedent-focused regulation",
      "Social awareness"
    ],
    answer: "Antecedent-focused regulation"
  },
  {
     numb:42,
    question: "42.___ is when people change their outward emotional expressions without feeling the actual emotion they show.",
    options: [
      "deep acting",
      "depth acting",
      "surface acting",
      "small acting",
      "none of the above"
    ],
    answer:"surface acting"
  },
  {
     numb:43,
    question: "43.Which of the following leadership styles can result in people get overwhelmed & burnt out",
    options: [
      "Pace-setting",
      "Coaching",
      "Democratic",
      "Affiliative",
      "Authoritative"
    ],
    answer:"Pace-setting"
  },
  {
     numb:44,
    question: "44.___ is the public face of emotion in leadership.",
    options: [
      "Emotional awareness",
      "Social regulation",
      "Sympathy",
      "Emotional labor",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    answer:"Emotional labor"
   
  },
  {
     numb:45,
    question: "45.Leaders high on empathy will prefer to use ___.",
    options: [
      "surface acting",
      "sympathy",
      "anger",
      "deep acting",
      "coercion"
    ],
    answer:"deep acting"
  },
  {
     numb:46,
    question: "46.Emotional intelligence is a crucial component of ___.",
    options: [
      "Analytical intelligence",
      "Divergent thinking",
      "Social intelligence",
      "Convergent thinking",
      "Creative interests"
    ],
    answer:"Social intelligence"
  },
  {
     numb:47,
    question: "47.Accurately labeling emotion is also called as ___.",
    options: [
      "Emotional expertise",
      "Emotional awareness",
      "Emotional contagion",
      "Empathy",
      "Emotional literacy"
    ],
    answer:"Emotional literacy"
  },
  {
    numb: 48,
    question: "48._____ is the type of diversity in the context of education which refers to the numerical & proportional representation of students from diverse groups in the student population",
    answer: "Structural diversity",
    options: [
      "Structural diversity",
      "Numerical diversity",
      "Proportionate diversity",
      "Interactional diversity",
      "Constructional diversity"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:49,
    question: "49.Each type of diversity is ___",
    answer: "complementary to each other",
    options: [
      "complementary to each other",
      "competitive in nature",
      "independent of each other",
      "detrimental to each other",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:50,
    question: "50._____ refers to an understanding that certain common values exist across diverse ethnic groups & group conflict often can be constructive if used appropriately",
    answer: "Compatibility of differences",
    options: [
      "Civic engagement",
      "Compatibility of differences",
      "Cultural engagement",
      "Learning outcomes",
      "Differential engagement"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:51,
    question: "51.Major transformations in knowledge sector due to globalization and IT revolution include",
    answer: "all of the above",
    options: [
      "virtual universities",
      "e-courses",
      "app based learning",
      "online packages",
      "all of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 52,
    question: "52.In India, the Ministry of Human Resource Development has taken some initiatives like implementing NAB, where NAB stands for",
    answer: "National Accreditation Board",
    options: [
      "National Award Board",
      "National Award Bureau",
      "National Accreditation Bureau",
      "National Acceptance Board",
      "National Accreditation Board"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:53,
    question: "53.Due to escalating fees in developed nations, the students from these countries are choosing to study & take their degrees from ___",
    answer: "both a & b",
    options: [
      "reputed institutes of developing Asian countries",
      "online courses",
      "both a & b",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:54,
    question: "54.Which of the following has been observed to be true for new generation learners?",
    answer: "a, b and c",
    options: [
      "expect a pass for anything they submit, irrespective of its quality",
      "not as self-reliant as the previous generations",
      "use the peer group reference for making any academic decision like where to enroll & which subject to take",
      "only c",
      "a, b and c"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:55,
    question: "55.The higher education sector of which countries is larger than that of India?",
    answer: "China and the U.S.A.",
    options: [
      "China and the U.S.A.",
      "Japan and China",
      "China and Singapore",
      "USA and Bangladesh",
      "Canada and Singapore"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:56,
    question: "56.Taiwan being the major designer of IT hardware is also considering the making of ___ by merging some of its top technological universities",
    answer: "'Asian MIT'",
    options: [
      "'Asian MIT'",
      "'Asian Oxford'",
      "'Asian Harvard'",
      "'Asian Cambridge'",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 57,
    question: "57.The three major areas to be considered in the pedagogical approach of enhancing students' understanding of international contexts, competition & the meaning of globalization include the following except",
    answer: "money",
    options: [
      "linguistics",
      "money",
      "curriculum",
      "leadership"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 58,
    question: "58._____ is the type of diversity in the context of education which refers to the numerical & proportional representation of students from diverse groups in the student population",
    answer: "Structural diversity",
    options: [
      "Structural diversity",
      "Numerical diversity",
      "Proportionate diversity",
      "Interactional diversity",
      "Constructional diversity"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:59,
    question: "59.Each type of diversity is ___",
    answer: "complementary to each other",
    options: [
      "complementary to each other",
      "competitive in nature",
      "independent of each other",
      "detrimental to each other",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:60,
    question: "60._____ refers to an understanding that certain common values exist across diverse ethnic groups & group conflict often can be constructive if used appropriately",
    answer: "Compatibility of differences",
    options: [
      "Civic engagement",
      "Compatibility of differences",
      "Cultural engagement",
      "Learning outcomes",
      "Differential engagement"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 61,
    question: "61.Major transformations in knowledge sector due to globalization and IT revolution include",
    answer: "all of the above",
    options: [
      "virtual universities",
      "e-courses",
      "app based learning",
      "online packages",
      "all of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:62,
    question: "62.In India, the Ministry of Human Resource Development has taken some initiatives like implementing NAB, where NAB stands for",
    answer: "National Accreditation Board",
    options: [
      "National Award Board",
      "National Award Bureau",
      "National Accreditation Bureau",
      "National Acceptance Board",
      "National Accreditation Board"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 63,
    question: "63.Due to escalating fees in developed nations, the students from these countries are choosing to study & take their degrees from ___",
    answer: "both a & b",
    options: [
      "reputed institutes of developing Asian countries",
      "online courses",
      "both a & b",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 64,
    question: "64.Which of the following has been observed to be true for new generation learners?",
    answer: "a, b and c",
    options: [
      "expect a pass for anything they submit, irrespective of its quality",
      "not as self-reliant as the previous generations",
      "use the peer group reference for making any academic decision like where to enroll & which subject to take",
      "only c",
      "a, b and c"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:65,
    question: "65.The higher education sector of which countries is larger than that of India?",
    answer: "China and the U.S.A.",
    options: [
      "China and the U.S.A.",
      "Japan and China",
      "China and Singapore",
      "USA and Bangladesh",
      "Canada and Singapore"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:66,
    question: "66.Taiwan being the major designer of IT hardware is also considering the making of ___ by merging some of its top technological universities",
    answer: "'Asian MIT'",
    options: [
      "'Asian MIT'",
      "'Asian Oxford'",
      "'Asian Harvard'",
      "'Asian Cambridge'",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:67,
    question: "67.The three major areas to be considered in the pedagogical approach of enhancing students' understanding of international contexts, competition & the meaning of globalization include the following except",
    answer: "money",
    options: [
      "linguistics",
      "money",
      "curriculum",
      "leadership"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 68,
    question: "68.The new paradigms of education advocate for ___",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "'No child left behind'",
      "Personalized learning assistance",
      "Quality education to all",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 69,
    question: "69.Which of the following is true for metacognition?",
    answer: "It can occur before the event, after the event or simultaneously",
    options: [
      "It occurs before the cognitive event",
      "It occurs after the cognitive event",
      "It occurs simultaneously with the cognitive event",
      "It can occur before the event, after the event or simultaneously",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:70,
    question: "70.___ knowledge is knowing about when & why declarative & procedural knowledge are relevant to tasks (effective strategies)",
    answer: "Conditional",
    options: [
      "Conceptual",
      "Contextual",
      "Conditional",
      "Causational",
      "Creative"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:71,
    question: "71.___ is the fit between meta-cognition & performance",
    answer: "Calibration",
    options: [
      "Calibration",
      "Meta-cognitive monitoring",
      "Meta-cognitive control",
      "Self-regulated learning",
      "Correlation"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 72,
    question: "72.Which of the following is not a dimension of the learning environment focused on by cognitive apprenticeship?",
    answer: "Communication",
    options: [
      "Content",
      "Method",
      "Sequence",
      "Sociology",
      "Communication"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:73,
    question: "73.Which of the following is an experiential learning method?",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "Role-play",
      "Visualization",
      "Simulation",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 74,
    question: "74.___ learning includes presentation of lessons through multimedia material i.e. text, animation, graphics, video & sound",
    answer: "Web-based",
    options: [
      "Problem-based",
      "Web-based",
      "Information-based",
      "Collaborative",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:75,
    question: "75.Games are based on the theory of ___ as they use fantasy, control, challenge, curiosity & adventure to motivate players.",
    answer: "intrinsic motivation",
    options: [
      "fantasy",
      "extrinsic motivation",
      "intrinsic motivation",
      "imagination",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 76,
    question: "76.Which of the following is an innovative pedagogy of learning?",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "Game-based learning",
      "Mobile learning",
      "Puzzle-based learning",
      "Project - based learning",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 77,
    question: "77.In ___ model of blended learning, most learning is done in the online environment; face-to-face teaching is still available, but for small groups / individuals on a requirement basis.",
    answer: "flex",
    options: [
      "online lab",
      "rotation",
      "flex",
      "self blend",
      "online driver"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 78,
    question: "78.Turnaround Leadership brings together a distinct profile of ___ & cognitive ability",
    answer: "emotional intelligence",
    options: [
      "emotional intelligence",
      "musical intelligence",
      "spatial intelligence",
      "naturalistic intelligence",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:79,
    question: "79.Which of the following is a role taken up by turnaround leaders?",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "Learn",
      "Teach",
      "Model",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 80,
    question: "80.___ means possessing requisite capacity & knowledge required for management, possessing the key skills & knowledge required to deliver the tasks that make up the specific job",
    answer: "Competence",
    options: [
      "Competence",
      "Interest",
      "Cognitive capacity",
      "Creative intelligence",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:81,
    question: "81.Which of the following is not a dimension of the 'Turnaround Academic Leadership Capability Framework'?",
    answer: "Athletic competencies",
    options: [
      "Personal capabilities",
      "Interpersonal capabilities",
      "Cognitive capabilities",
      "Role-specific competencies",
      "Athletic competencies"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 82,
    question: "82.ICT for supporting learning on-line courses for distance - learning through ___",
    answer: "all of the above",
    options: [
      "multimedia resources",
      "e-conferencing & video conferences",
      "discussion forums",
      "live lectures (video streaming)",
      "all of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 83,
    question: "83.Turnaround leaders can manage relationships with stakeholders through ___",
    answer: "All the above",
    options: [
      "Building a sustainable learning community",
      "Monitoring & self-evaluation",
      "Networking with other agencies",
      "Performance evaluation & management",
      "All the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 84,
    question: "84.___ is the term for using a combination of competition & cooperation for bringing change within the system",
    answer: "Co-opetitions",
    options: [
      "Compete-eration",
      "Co-opetitions",
      "Collaborative competition",
      "Combinative cooperation",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 85,
    question: "85.Which of the following is not an attitude under the 'Entrepreneurship Competencies Model'?",
    answer: "Procrastination",
    options: [
      "Self-efficacy",
      "Proactiveness",
      "Procrastination",
      "Innovativeness",
      "Perseverance"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:86,
    question: "86.___ is a factor in the 'Academic Entrepreneurship-cum-Performance' model",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "Academic mindset",
      "Academic perseverance",
      "Academic behaviors",
      "Social skills",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 87,
    question: "87.By taking the role of a ___ educational entrepreneurs demonstrate what is possible when resources are used differently & point the way toward how policy & practice might be changed in the light of what they accomplish.",
    answer: "change agent",
    options: [
      "change agent",
      "content agent",
      "context agent",
      "private agent",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 88,
    question: "88.___ refers to independent learning where students learn at their own pace in different times and spaces.",
    answer: "asynchronous learning",
    options: [
      "whenever and wherever learning",
      "synchronous learning",
      "asynchronous learning",
      "paced learning",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:89,
    question: "89.Zoom, MS Teams or Google meet classes held during the pandemic refer to ___ type of learning.",
    answer: "synchronous learning",
    options: [
      "synchronous learning",
      "asynchronous learning",
      "synthetic learning",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:90,
    question: "90.Which of the following is true regarding teachers' role in online learning during the pandemic?",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "Increased focus on individual needs and learning styles",
      "Increased expectancy to be available for students",
      "Encourage collaboration for motivation",
      "Encourage higher participation through creative methods",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 91,
    question: "91.Which of the following is not an effective way to motivate online learners?",
    answer: "Establishing a sense of social isolation",
    options: [
      "Establishing a sense of social isolation",
      "Online collaboration",
      "Prompt feedback",
      "Designing and organizing activities"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 92,
    question: "92.Which of the following is not a component of the 3Cs useful in the post-pandemic new normal education setting?",
    answer: "Caste",
    options: [
      "Consistency",
      "Caste",
      "Creativity",
      "Community"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 93,
    question: "93.High levels of digital task engagement may result in ___",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "conceptual change",
      "psychological well being",
      "improved understanding about students'",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 94,
    question: "94.Which of the following does not come under the 5E framework in the context of online flipped classes?",
    answer: "evacuate",
    options: [
      "engage",
      "evacuate",
      "explore",
      "explain",
      "evaluate"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 95, 
    question: "95.Effective feedback is ___.",
    answer: "all of the above",
    options: [
      "specific",
      "descriptive",
      "student-initiated",
      "time appropriate",
      "all of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 96,
    question: "96.Mid-term and end-term exams are types of ___",
    answer: "summative assessment",
    options: [
      "summative assessment",
      "collective assessment",
      "formative assessment",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 97,
    question: "97.Before feedback can be given, ___ clarifies learning intentions for students and sets the context for feedback.",
    answer: "feed-up",
    options: [
      "feed-up",
      "feedback loop",
      "feed-forward",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 98,
    question: "98.Andragogy means the understanding of the science and practice of ___",
    answer: "adult learning",
    options: [
      "adult learning",
      "children learning",
      "women learning",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:99,
    question: "99.Which of the following is not a principle of andragogy?",
    answer: "physical orientation",
    options: [
      "self-direction",
      "experience",
      "mentorship",
      "transformation",
      "physical orientation"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 100,
    question: "100.The best micro-learning content is ___",
    answer: "all of the above",
    options: [
      "under 6 minutes",
      "focused on a single concept",
      "specific to an objective",
      "all of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 101,
    question: "101.Which of the following is not among the key metrics to show which courses are engaging learners, and which could use an instructional-design rethink?",
    answer: "number of books purchased by learner",
    options: [
      "total time spent learning",
      "learner progress",
      "qualitative feedback",
      "assessment breakdowns",
      "number of books purchased by learner"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 102,
    question: "102.Learning transfer is a process of ___",
    answer: "internalizing, comprehending and applying",
    options: [
      "rote learning, memorizing and processing",
      "memorizing, resting and applying",
      "internalizing, ignoring, processing",
      "comprehending, evaluating, applying",
      "internalizing, comprehending and applying"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 103,
    question: "103.The solution for the learning need of willingness is ___",
    answer: "transferable skills",
    options: [
      "just-in-time learning",
      "learner-analytics",
      "social learning environment",
      "transferable skills"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 104,
    question: "104.Which of the following is a benefit of using LMS for self-paced learning?",
    answer: "all of the above",
    options: [
      "collaborative social learning tools",
      "chatting about ideas",
      "useful resources",
      "discussing difficult chapters",
      "all of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 105,
    question: "105.Which of the following is not used to fulfill the need for learning by doing?",
    answer: "lectures",
    options: [
      "simulations",
      "animations",
      "interactive-activities",
      "experiential exercises",
      "lectures"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 106,
    question: "106.___ is also called \"Self-determined Learning\".",
    answer: "Heutagogy",
    options: [
      "Heutagogy",
      "Pedagogy",
      "Ontology",
      "Andragogy",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 107,
    question: "107.Which of the following is an example of lifelong learning?",
    answer: "all of the above",
    options: [
      "developing a skill of cooking",
      "learning a new language",
      "learning how to use a new phone",
      "enrolling in an educational degree",
      "all of the above"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 108,
    question: "108.NEP 2020 intends to achieve primarily which of the following Sustainable Development Goals (SDG)?",
    answer: "SDG 4: Inclusive and equitable quality education",
    options: [
      "SDG 4: Inclusive and equitable quality education",
      "SDG 6: Clean water and sanitation",
      "SDG 8: Decent work and economic growth",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 109,
    question: "109.Which of the following is not included as a stage in the structure recommended by NEP 2020?",
    answer: "Senior",
    options: [
      "Preparatory",
      "Foundational",
      "Secondary",
      "Middle",
      "Senior"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 110,
    question: "110.What is the full form of NTA?",
    answer: "National Testing Agency",
    options: [
      "New Testing Act",
      "National Testing Act",
      "New Testing Agency",
      "National Testing Agency",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb:111,
    question: "111.In higher education system, the expected student-faculty ratio is ___.",
    answer: "30:1",
    options: [
      "2:1",
      "5:1",
      "10:1",
      "20:1",
      "30:1"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 112,
    question: "112.Which of the following is not a merit of higher education policies in NEP 2020?",
    answer: "bureaucratic",
    options: [
      "student-centric",
      "bureaucratic",
      "autonomic",
      "research and innovation focused"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 113,
    question: "113.Contemplative education is a philosophy of higher education that integrates ___ and ___ into academic study.",
    answer: "introspection and experiential learning",
    options: [
      "introspection and passive learning",
      "networking and experiential learning",
      "passive learning and assessment",
      "introspection and experiential learning"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 114,
    question: "114.Broadly, there are ___ main ways that contemplative practices are incorporated",
    answer: "three",
    options: [
      "two",
      "three",
      "ten",
      "five",
      "fifteen"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 115,
    question: "115.SEL stands for ___",
    answer: "social-emotional learning",
    options: [
      "self-efficacy in learning",
      "social effective learning",
      "standard emotional learning",
      "social-emotional learning"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 116,
    question: "116.Open awareness (in the context of mindfulness) is also known as ___",
    answer: "open monitoring",
    options: [
      "open systems",
      "open mindedness",
      "openness",
      "open monitoring"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 117,
    question: "117.___ component of transformative learning refers to experiences narrated/explained in a logical and rational manner that can bring about transformative learning.",
    answer: "rational disclosure",
    options: [
      "rational disclosure",
      "critical reflection",
      "centrality of experience",
      "disorienting dilemma",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 118,
    question: "118.The Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs), were adopted by all United Nations Member States in ___.",
    answer: "2015",
    options: [
      "2015",
      "2010",
      "2019",
      "2022",
      "2023"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 119,
    question: "119.SDGs replaced MDGs. In this context, what is the full form of 'MDGs'?",
    answer: "Millennium Development Goals",
    options: [
      "Massive Development Goals",
      "Millennium Development Goals",
      "Micro Development Goals",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 120,
    question: "120.The aim of SDG 2 is ___.",
    answer: "all of the above",
    options: [
      "end hunger",
      "achieve food security",
      "achieve improved nutrition",
      "promote sustainable agriculture",
      "all of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 121,
    question: "121.Which SDG focuses on investing in solar, wind and thermal power, improving energy productivity, and ensuring energy for all",
    answer: "Goal 7",
    options: [
      "Goal 5",
      "Goal 6",
      "Goal 7",
      "Goal 8",
      "Goal 9"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 122,
    question: "122.SDG 4 has been broken down into ___ number of targets based on the different roles to be fulfilled by different players in the institution",
    answer: "ten",
    options: [
      "two",
      "five",
      "seven",
      "ten"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 123,
    question: "123.Which of the following is an essential characteristic of ESD?",
    answer: "All of the above",
    options: [
      "promotes lifelong learning",
      "is culturally appropriate",
      "engages formal, non-formal and informal education",
      "is interdisciplinary",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 124,
    question: "124.GCED is a strategic area of UNESCO's Education Sector programme and builds on the work of Peace and Human Rights Education. GCED stands for ___.",
    answer: "Global Citizenship Education",
    options: [
      "Global Competitive Education and Development",
      "Global Citizenship Education",
      "Global Citizenship Education and Development",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 125,
    question: "125.Under the GCED umbrella, UNESCO has several special themes. Which of the following is included in them?",
    answer: "all of the above",
    options: [
      "promotion of the rule of law through global citizenship education",
      "preventing violent extremism through education",
      "Languages in education",
      "all of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 126,
    question: "126.In general citizenship education should result in educated people with certain characteristics. Among them, ___ refers to supporting a certain idea through reasoning.",
    answer: "advocacy",
    options: [
      "advocacy",
      "conciliation",
      "representation",
      "responsibility",
      "research"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 127,
    question: "127.Which of the following is not one of the sustainable leadership skills?",
    answer: "think short term for immediate gains",
    options: [
      "manage complexity",
      "communicate vision",
      "exercise judgment",
      "challenge and innovate",
      "think short term for immediate gains"
    ]
  }
];



